oh
we i like these bumper plates right here
yes sir these black bumper plates from
rep fitness not only do they look pretty
hanging on our barbing garage jim i mean
i really don't even want to touch them i
don't want to mess them up that's not
gonna do us any good will it they're
also super durable and they're gonna be
able to withstand all the punishment you
could ask for in a pair of bumper plates
let's get started on this video today
what's good my friends it's jake back in
the barbing garage gym and for today's
review i've got the rep fitness bumper
plates in this video i'm going to walk
you through everything these bad boys
have to offer the price the pros the
cons and of course who should and who
should not make this their next purchase
but before we get going as always gotta
let you know we have reviewed a bunch of
bumper plates on barbin.com if you want
to find out more about our list and find
out for yourself which one we like the
best just google barbind best bumper
plates and you can read all about it
okay so what do i like about these rep
fitness bumper plates yeah they look
really nice and it's a really common
phrase in the sports world that if you
look good you'll feel good and then
you'll play good that's no exception
here they look awesome but thanks to
those steel inserts that are wrapped in
a rubber coating it's going to add to
the durability and maybe even have these
last a very long time but they're also
going to protect the barbell whenever
you drop it or slam it into the ground
and may even potentially protect your
floors as well as any surrounding
equipment while you're lifting i really
like how thick the 10 pound plates are
they're an inch thick a little bit
thicker than normal and the 45 pound
plates are actually a little bit thinner
than most 45 pound bumper plates that's
going to allow you to really load up the
weight on either side of your bar and
make room for additional plates yeah
most bumper plates do come in individual
pairs or full set i really like how rep
fitness has their sets go up to 370
pounds which is more than some other
competition out there
[Music]
okay so what about those potential cons
now with these bumper plates well as you
can see they do not feature a handle a
lot of times you'll find bumper plates
to have a handle that's really helpful
in terms of loading and unloading your
barbell as well as specific exercises
such as a front shoulder raise that's
really nice when it comes to those
and this is actually a twofer here these
plates are pretty expensive there are
cheaper options out there you know these
might fall out of your price range so if
it does i'd suggest those cheaper
options but those might have iron
inserts instead of steel like you'll
find here and sticking with that price
if you don't have much usage for a set
of bumper plates i'd probably just avoid
it all together
okay so let's talk a little bit more
about money here as i mentioned these
bumper plates a little bit expensive a
pair of 10-pound plates that's going to
cost you about 70 bucks while a pair of
45 pound plates that's going to run you
near 200
so the more cost efficient way of going
about this is definitely to get the set
if you're new to weightlifting if you're
a beginner i would definitely suggest
the 160 pound set it's gonna run you
about 360 bucks but if you're a power
lifter it's definitely best to go and
snag that 370 pound set it's gonna cost
you about 800 bucks
now i know it's a lot of money but
bumper plates tend to be more expensive
than your traditional weight plate in
general
that's due to the extra rubber coating
it's going to add to that lifespan and
since these plates could last you 10
plus years i think it makes that price
tag worth it in my opinion
[Music]
all right guys let's talk about the
build now with these bumper plates as i
mentioned they do have steel inserts
that are wrapped in a low bounce virgin
rubber which as you may assume it's
going to keep them from bouncing too
much which is really ideal for at-home
usage the 10-pound plates are actually
thicker than most 10-pound bumper plates
a lot of times you'll find them to be
about eight tenths of an inch well this
is actually one inch thick it's gonna
add to that durability and maybe even
prevent these from bending or tacoing
over repeated use
the 15 pound plates are about one and a
quarter inch thick these 25 pound plates
are about one and three quarters of an
inch thick and i don't have the 35 pound
plates for you guys today but those are
a shade under two and a half inches
thick
and another really cool thing here is
these 45 pound plates are actually
thinner than most 45-pound bumper plates
most of the time you're gonna find that
a 45-pound bumper plate about three
inches thick
these are shade under that
and that's going to really help you out
in terms of loading up your barbell to
get a super heavy lift
now more about the details here
yeah these are black in color if you
wanted to go for the more traditional
olympic style colored bumper plates rep
fitness actually has those available for
purchase but those are even more
expensive than these are the white
lettering is really going to help you
out in terms of knowing exactly which
bumper plate you're going to grab for
your lifts and i already talked about it
they don't have a handle sometimes
bumper plates do have handles that's
really helpful when you're going to load
or unload your barbell as well as
performing a standalone exercise that
bumper plates can offer you and since
they're rounded you actually can use
these for roll outs with a barbell
[Music]
all right so i already told you guys you
can purchase these plates in individual
pairs or as a full set i'm going to tell
you some more about that now so
individual pairs range from 5 pounds to
45 pounds while the sets are gonna range
from 160 all the way up to 370 pounds
now in terms of picking which set is
best for you
really just depends on your overall
strength if you wanted the 370 pound
option you're going to get 645 pound
plates to go along with two 25 15 and 10
pound plates for you to use but if you
wanted that 160 pound set you're only
going to get two 45 25 and 10 pound
plates now over time as you get stronger
and find yourself needing more plates
you can always head over to
repfitness.com
and you can purchase more individual
pairs
[Music]
all right so let's talk about who should
purchase these rep fitness bumper plates
well if you're somebody looking to fill
out your home gym with a durable long
lasting set of plates this is a really
good option to consider they do have
that steel insert and they're wrapped in
that low bounce virgin rubber it's going
to increase the lifespan of the plates
but also might even protect your barbell
your floor and maybe even protect your
equipment that's surrounding you from
potential harm it's really cool you can
purchase these in individual pairs but
the sets include seven different options
for you to choose from of various weight
and anybody who's wanting to focus on
olympic or crossfit style lifts you're
gonna love that you can drop these from
various heights without damaging them
all right so let's talk about who does
not need to purchase these bumper plates
well like i said they're kind of
expensive
if you find these to fall out of your
price range i would suggest a cheaper
option but the good thing about these
they do have steel inserts and some of
those cheaper options are going to have
an iron insert meaning they're not going
to be as durable as these are right here
the lack of a handle might bug some
people when you're loading or unloading
your plate or it might be a little bit
more difficult when you're doing those
front shoulder raises i was talking
about earlier if you have one with a
handle it might be a little bit easier
to get a good grip since it would be on
the inside as opposed to the outside and
since these 45 pound plates are thinner
it's really cool and really helpful in
terms of loading up your barbell
but at the same time they might not be
as durable as a 45 pound plate from a
competitor brand that does have that
three inch thickness
all right guys that's all i have for you
today on the rep fitness black bumper
plates i personally love these plates
they perform well they look great
they're a really good option to consider
for your home gym that low bounce virgin
rubber and the steel inserts gonna make
them super durable without tearing up
your personal space
extra thick 10 pound plates gonna add
even more to the durability of those
while these thin 45 pound plates are
going to help you to load up your
barbell for a super heavy lift
thanks for watching everybody as always
i hope this video is helpful for you
guys and really showed you more of what
these bad boys can do in your weight
room in the meantime do a quick google
search type in barbin rep fitness black
bumper plates review you can read more
details on this product i'll catch you
guys later
you